《外星居民》前情提要
Previously on "Resident Alien."
被困在外星上
Stranded on an alien planet.
为了活下来  并完成我的任务
In order to survive and complete my mission,
我得想办法用人形融入这里
I would have to somehow fit in with the human life forms.
哈里·万德斯本格医生
Dr. Harry Vanderspeigle?
昨晚镇上发生了一起谋杀案
We had a murder in town last night.
我们要你来帮我们看看尸体
We need you to come down and take a look at the body.
-搞什么鬼  -你没死
- What the mother hell? - You're not dead.
阿斯塔是护士
Asta's the nurse.
是新来的那个医生
It's the new doctor.
-他是外星人  -等等  外星人
- He's an alien. - Wait, an alien?
你到底教了这孩子什么鬼啊
What the hell are you teaching this kid, huh?
一个错误
One mistake.
一个为了生存而犯下的小错误
Just one mistake made out of necessity for survival.
我别无选择
I had no choice
只能杀死了那个叫哈里·万德斯本格的人
but to kill the human known as Harry Vanderspeigle.
我是在保护自己
I was just defending myself.
在我把他
How was I supposed to know
从冰上扔下去时
when I threw him on top of the ice
我怎么知道他会消失在湖里
he would disappear into the lake?
我是一个外星人
I am an alien.
我根本不知道地球是怎么样
I don't know every little detail about how Earth works.
一切都会没事的
Everything will be fine.
我只需要赶在别人之前找到尸体
I just need to find that body before someone else does.
外星居民
第一季第三集
睡觉  人类弱小又低效的另一个有力实例
Sleep: another example of humans being weak and inefficient.
他们的身体每天必须休眠八小时
Their bodies must shut down for eight hours every single day,
不然就不能正常工作
or they don't work properly.
拜托到六点了  拜托到六点了
Please be 6:00 A. M. Please be 6:00 A. M.
有好多事要做
So much to do.
我要找到湖里的那具尸体  找到我的设备
I have to find that body in the lake, find my device,
我在山上炸裂的飞船碎片
the pieces of my ship that broke off over the mountains,
我要杀了那个孩子
I have to kill that kid--
差点就忘了
mm, almost forgot about that.
灭绝人类
Exterminate the human race.
牛奶  得弄点牛奶
Milk, gotta get milk.
别忘了牛奶
Don't forget the milk.
也许可以弄点碎片
Maybe some cereal.
要是我睡不着
If I can't sleep,
至少可以学学提升我的医术
I can at least learn to be a better doctor.
环切包皮
Circumcision.
这是什么  眼部手术吗  点击
What is that, eye surgery? Click.
他们是野蛮人
They are a savage people.
焕然一新
Refreshed.
有足够的能量去登山了
Plenty of energy to climb a mountain.
你听说剧院边的那家中国餐馆
Did you hear that Chinese restaurant next to the theater
要关门了吗
is shutting down?
不是吧
No way.
我超喜欢那家店
I love that place.
李太太说她丈夫出轨
Yeah, Mrs. Lee accused her husband of cheating.
他们应该要离婚了
I guess they're splitting up.
什么  他们俩明明很般配
What? They're such a great couple.
可能只是一些误会
It's probably a misunderstanding.
我会找她聊聊的
I'll talk to her.
我听说有人想要把那里改成披萨快餐店
I hear someone wants to turn it into a gourmet pizza joint.
从另一方面来说
On the other hand,
他的确很有女人缘  所以吧
he was handsy with the ladies, so.
她也是迫于无奈了吧
She's gotta do what she's gotta do.
好了  你往高处扔  我往低处扔
Right. You throw high, I'll throw low?
-引线开  -引线开
- Spinner's on. - Spinner's on.
-保险移除  -保险移除
- Safety off. - Safety off.
三  二  一  拉
Three, two, one, pull.
漂亮的勾手
Nice hook shot.
球是命
Ball is life.
再说一遍试试
Yeah, say that again.
-球是命  -不  别
- Ball is life. - No, don't--
-别说两遍...  -球是命
- don't say it twi-- - Ball is life.
你总是这样
You always do that.
这是我找到的第三片飞船碎片
This is the third piece of my ship that I've found.
我的设备肯定就在附近
My device has to be nearby.
这里不止我一个人
I'm not alone up here.
这可不妙
This is bad.
我感觉到我的后虹膜皱褶和我的睾丸收紧了
I just felt my rear iris pucker and my testicles tighten.
我的味道没有变
My taint remains unchanged.
雪崩覆盖了我的搜索区域
That avalanche covering my search area
让我的工作几乎倒退了一周
has set me back at least a week.
这些人类自以为总是能跑来破坏我的计划
These humans think they can constantly thwart my plans.
不可能了
Well, no more.
真是太扯淡了
This is some bullshit!
你好  我叫凯特·霍索恩
Hi, I'm Kate Hawthorne.
我的丈夫是本  镇长
My husband is Ben, the mayor.
我见过他  身上一股汤味
I met him. He smells like soap.
就是他
Yeah, that's him.
我的儿子几天前从你的诊所逃走
My son ran out of your office a few days ago.
我能进去吗  拜托
Can I come in? Please?
好  稍等一下
Yes, just one minute.
我有事要和你说
I need to talk to you about something.
我的儿子麦克斯和我说你是外新人
My son Max told me you're an alien.
然后呢
What's that then?
他还和我说你闯进了他的卧室
He also told me that you broke into his bedroom
想要杀死他
and tried to kill him.
有意思
That's interesting.
他到底怎么了
What is wrong with him?
他为什么要编这些事
Why is he making things up?
-你觉得他在说谎  -他当然在说谎
- You think he's lying. - Of course he's lying.
你显然不是外星人
You're obviously not an alien.
他之前从诊所跑了  我真是尴尬死了
I'm so embarrassed that he ran out of the clinic.
真抱歉打扰你了
I'm sorry to bother you.
这种事我通常是跟山姆聊的  可他...
I normally talk to Sam about this stuff, but he's--
你知道的
well, you know.
他死了
He's dead.
-对  -你没什么好担心的
- Yeah. - Well, you don't have anything to worry about.
我不是外星人
I'm not an alien.
太可惜了  我听说外星人还挺酷的
Unfortunately. I hear they're pretty cool.
谢谢你过来
Thank you for coming over.
只是...我没法让我儿子放下这个想法
It's just-- I can't get my son off of this.
他不只是编造故事  他...
And it's not just the stories, he's--
他还画了画
he's drawn pictures.
非常多的画  你看看
Lots and lots of pictures. Look at them.
太让人担心了
They're disturbing.
还有那个外星人  他...
And that alien? I mean--
他居然说服副警长画了这个
he even convinced the deputy to draw this.
你看看  恶心死了
Look at this, it's disgusting.
我光是看着就想吐了
Makes me want to throw up just looking at it.
有的人以为人类就够丑了呢
Some people think humans are ugly.
我不知道该怎么办了
I just don't know what to do.
麦克斯不肯睡觉  不肯吃东西
Max won't sleep, he won't eat,
实话说吧  他快把我逼疯了
and, frankly, he is driving me crazy.
你是医生
You're a doctor.
有什么我们能做的吗
Is there anything that we can do?
搬走
Move.
-什么  -搬得远远的
- What? - Far away from here.
找所新学校  开始新生活
A new school, a new life.
如果麦克斯知道自己再也不会踏入科罗拉多州
If Max knows that he is never setting a foot in Colorado
或是美国西部
or the Western United States again,
我觉得他会成为一个快乐的孩子
I think that he will be a happy kid.
我们在这里有工作
Uh, we have jobs.
我丈夫是镇长
My husband is the mayor.
苏格兰也招镇长
Scotland needs mayors.
我在书上看到的
I read it in a book.
我们不会搬家
We're not moving.
当然了
Ah, of course!
不搬
Not.
他可能只是在寻求关注
He's probably just looking for attention.
对
Yeah.
可能有道理
I guess that makes sense.
我白天会尽量避开麦克斯
I try and steer clear of Max during the day.
有一个在学校工作的妈并不轻松
Having a mom who works at school isn't the easiest thing.
忽视  是你的错
Neglect. It's your fault.
这样的话  你可以走了
And with that, you can go.
嗯...我...
Uh... yeah, well, I...
看来我就尽量多陪陪他吧
guess I'll just try spending more time with him.
我得承认  我觉得自己都快疯了
Gotta be honest, I feel like I'm losing my mind.
麦克斯再不放弃外星人的事
Max doesn't drop the alien thing,
我就要杀了他
I'm gonna kill him.
你我都是
You and me both.
谢谢你做的一切
Thank you so much for everything--
好吧
'Kay.
早啊  混蛋
Good morning, dickhead.
你不能那么叫我  那是个不好的词
Can't call me that. That's a nasty word.
对不起了  小杂碎
Oh, I'm sorry, shit-for-brains.
你没礼貌  你还偷了我的传单
You're inappropriate and you stole my flyers.
你还想把它们贴回去吗
Do you wanna put them back up?
尽管去啊
Go ahead.
反正也没人相信你  连你父母都不信
No one believes you, anyway, not even your parents.
去跟人说我是外星人啊
Tell people I am an alien.
爬到镇上最高的塔上
Climb to the highest tower in town
昭告天下啊
and shout it to everyone.
现在没有塔了  傻子外星人
We don't have towers, you dumb alien.
不  我...
No, I--
我知道没塔  我那是个比喻
I know that; it was a figure of speech.
才不是
No, it wasn't.
我的天  你还真以为我们有塔
Oh, my God, you actually thought we had towers.
-我没有  -你太笨了
- I did not! - You're so stupid.
"你好  我是外星人  我以为这是有城堡的年代
"Hi, I'm an alien and I think it's castle times
还有塔这种东西"
and there are towers."
我是在试探你是不是以为这里有塔
I was testing to see if you thought there were towers,
算你走运  你过关了
and you're lucky you passed.
-我现在要去上学了  -等等
- Well, I'm gonna go to school now. - Wait.
希望不会有塔砸在我身上
I hope a tower doesn't fall on me
因为我们活在自欺欺人的时代
because we live in make-believe times.
是你以为现在还有塔
You're the one who thinks there's towers!
混蛋
Dickhead.
垃...
Assh--
垃圾
Asshole.
阿丝儿塔
Hey, Ass-ta.
是阿斯塔  艾伦  你知道的
It's Ah-sta, Ellen. You knew that.
抱歉  肯定是我的加拿大基因在作祟
Sorry. Must be the Canadian in me.
在你假想的国界线这头  我叫阿斯塔
Well, on this side of the imaginary border, it's Ah-sta.
帕斯塔  抓马  阿斯塔  还有什么能帮你的
Pasta, drama, Ah-sta. What else can I do for you?
阿斯塔  V医生需要些处方签
Ah-sta, Dr. V needs some prescription pads,
可我找不着
but I can't find any.
你都找了哪里
Well, where have you looked?
我还没找呢  你去帮他拿行吗
I haven't looked yet. Can you get them?
员工间
你在干什么
Whoa, what are you doing?
-我太想要了  -什么
- I want that so badly. - Excuse me?
睡觉
Sleep.
我晚上睡不着  现在正努力学习怎么睡
I can't sleep at night. I'm trying to learn how.
好吧  停下来  怪瘆人的
Okay, well, please stop. It's creepy.
起来
Get up.
杰伊  醒醒
Jay, Jay, wake up.
醒一醒
Please wake up.
你在周围看到山姆的处方笺了吗
Have you seen one of Sam's prescription pads laying around?
少了一个
There's one missing.
我不知道他有没有带回家
I don't know if he took it home, I...
他以前总把它们放在办公室
he always used to keep them here.
这就是你叫醒我的原因吗
That's why you woke me up?
那你有没有看到
Well, have you seen it or not?
没有
Not.
我只是在这打工挣学分
I just work here for school credit.
我都不知道压舌板在哪
I barely know where the tongue depressors are.
我以为睡觉能让人感觉好点
I thought sleep was supposed to make you feel better.
放她一马吧
Cut her some slack.
她可能跟我们一样整晚没睡
She was probably up all night reeling like the rest of us.
你都不认识山姆  你为什么睡不着
You didn't even know Sam. Why can't you sleep?
湖里漂着一个死去的我
There's a dead me floating in the lake.
我找不到大脑的开关
I can't find the on/off switch in my brain.
你有冥想过吗
Do you ever meditate?
你说的冥想  是指安静地坐着
By meditate, do you mean sit peacefully
然后思考我想要杀的人吗
and think of all the people I want to kill?
有  我非常喜欢冥想
Yes. I like it very much.
-很好  -万德斯本格医生
- Good.  - Uh, Dr. Vanderspeigle,
我们需要你去市政厅一趟
we need you down at the town hall.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
又发现了一具尸体  这次是在湖里
There's another dead body. This time in the lake.
好吧
Okay.
市政厅
警长办公室
好了  好了
All right, all right,
现在外面有很多不实传言  好吗
now there's a lot of misinformation out there, okay?
大家都冷静一下
Everybody just needs to calm down.
得有人打开该死的窗户
And somebody need to open up a damn window
因为这里闻起来像汗津津的户外用品商店
'cause it smell like a sweaty REI store up in here.
什么
What?
我听说他们发现了一具尸体
I hear they found a body?
不  只有一只脚
No, just a foot.
杰克·鲁尼在湖里钓鱼时发现的
Jack Rooney found it fishing the lake.
哪个湖  我的湖吗
Which lake? My lake?
不是你的湖
Not your lake.
科罗拉多州的湖
Belongs to the state of Colorado.
你是想唬我吗
Oh, are you trying to impress me?
让我以为你有个湖
By making me think you own a lake?
没有  我不是那个意思
No, I'm not doing that.
你能不能别那么自我
Can maybe you be just a little less needy
稍微察言观色一下
and a little bit more sensitive?
毕竟有人死了
Because somebody's died, so.
拜托  我们能看看那只脚吗
Come on, can we see the foot?
怎么回事  那只脚是谁的
What's going on? Who does the foot belong to?
对啊  我们能摸摸吗
Yes, and can we touch it?
他们是被谋杀的吗
Were they murdered?
-好了  各位  各位  -脚是什么尺码
- Okay, folks, folks, folks.  - What size is it?
我们正在调查
This is an ongoing investigation
而我们现在只有...只有一只死者的脚
and all that we have now is...Is...Is a dead foot.
那只脚是我杀的那个人的
That foot belongs to the guy I killed.
据我们所知  只是
For all we know, you know, it's just, uh,
某个徒步者的脚被熊咬掉了
some hiker who got his foot ripped off by a bear.
有只杀人的熊逍遥法外吗
There's a killer bear on the loose?
我知道  是我的错
I know it. It's my own fault.
我应该多花点时间在湖里找
I should've spent more time searching the lake
然后少追超长电视剧《法律与秩序》
and less time watching "Law & Order" Marathons.
好了  所有人都闭嘴
All right! I want everybody to shut up!
我希望这里安静到
I want it so quiet in here,
能听到老鼠在棉花上尿尿的声音  明白吗
you can hear a mouse piss on cotton, you understand me?
不明白
No.
-好了  -好吧
- Now...  - Okay.
你们都知道
As you all know,
我们最近失去我们的山姆·霍奇斯
we recently lost one of our own, Sam Hodges,
他被谋杀了
who was murdered.
现在  在这里找到一只脚
Now, finding this here foot in there?
这是件好事
This is a good thing,
因为这意味着我们镇上没有杀人犯
'cause it means that we don't have a murderer in our town.
没有吗
We--we don't?
我们有一个连环杀手  大伙
We got ourselves a serial killer, y'all.
这算什么好事
How the hell is that a good thing?
连环杀手不会逃跑  躲藏
Serial killers don't run away and hide.
他们潜伏等待再次出手  所以更容易抓到他们
They lie in wait to strike again, so they're easier to catch.
如果我是个连环杀手
Hell, if I was a serial killer,
我现在就在这个房间里寻找下一个受害者
I'd be in this room right now looking for my next victim.
好了  别担心
All right. Whoa, whoa, whoa, don't worry!
我们要把这只脚送去丹佛做DNA检测
We're gonna send the foot to Denver for DNA testing.
只要我们查出是谁  就能抓住凶手
Once we find out who it is, we gon' catch this killer.
我不能让他们拿到DNA
I can't let them get that DNA.
他们会知道我就是湖里的那个死者
They'll know I'm dead lake man.
医生  你有什么...
Doctor, do you have anything that...
有什么要补充的吗
that you could...That you could add?
我好害怕
I am so scared!
真不错  医生  非常应景
Real nice, Doc. Real smooth, real smooth.
害怕是真的  我具有全部的迹象
Fear is real. I have all the signs.
手心出汗
Sweaty palms...
心跳加速
Elevated heartbeat...
帽子不错  怪胎
Nice hat, freak.
现在我的身体  能感受人类的情感
Now that I'm in this body, I'm feeling human emotions.
对不起咯
Sorry.
可怜的家伙
Poor guy.
我猜可能是船的螺旋桨打中了尸体
My guess is a boat propeller probably hit the dead body
把脚直接切下来了
and just chopped the foot right off.
白人男性
White male.
我觉得有四十多岁  八十公斤
I'm thinking late 40s, 180 pounds,
一米八以上
over six feet tall.
这是十二码的脚
That's a size twelve shoe.
天啊  要不是你有两只脚
Heck, if you didn't have two feet,
我都会以为这是你的脚
I'd think this thing was yours.
你真是个幽默的人
You are a funny, hilarious person.
总之  如果查出了匹配的DNA
Anyway, the medical examiner will let us know
法医会通知我们的
if we get a hit on the DNA.
对  我知道有可能匹配不到
No, I know there's a chance that there won't be,
但现在基因库里有那么多人的信息
but with so many people in the database these days,
还有那些祖先基因测试
all those ancestry testing kits.
我都做过一次
Even I did one.
结果我发现
Uh, I found out that, um,
我的亲生父亲
my real father
其实是我爸爸最好的朋友比尔
is actually my dad's best friend, Bill,
所以我告诉了我爸爸
so I told my dad
他就和我妈妈分手了
and he and my mom broke up
然后他离开搬去了俄亥俄州  所以...
and then he left town and he moved to Ohio, so...
我不推荐那些测试
I don't recommend those tests.
不管怎样  很快基因库里就只缺
Anyway, soon the only people who won't be in the database
隐士和婴儿的信息了
are hermits and babies.
绝对是我的脚
Definitely my foot.
我的种族进化出了令人惊叹的能力
It's amazing how my people have developed the ability
能够从细胞层面模仿其他生命体
to mimic other life forms on the cellular level.
我们是种无与伦比的...
We are an incredible...
我忘记关门了
And I forgot to close the door.
等你又古怪完了以后
When you're doing being next-level weird,
布里斯科一家在诊室等着
we have the Briscoes in the exam room.
找到我的袜子了
Oh, there's my sock.
在这呢
It's here.
我的那只脚去哪了
Where's my goddamn foot?
你偷了我那个死人的小脚丫
You stole my five dead little piggies,
更别提还有丽芙最爱的铁桶了
not to mention Liv's favorite bucket.
她总把汽水放在那里面
She puts her soda pop in there.
我可以帮忙  我是个病理学家
I can help. I am a pathologist.
你不需要把整只脚送到丹佛去
You don't need to send the whole foot to Denver.
那就把这玩意病理一下
Well, then pathologize the damn thing
给我整份DNA样本
and get me a DNA sample.
美国著名连环杀手
我们这出了个泰德·邦迪
We got some Ted Bundy shit going on around here,
我得在他下次出手之前阻止他
and I need to put a stop to it before he strikes again.
或者是她
Or she.
杀手可能是个女人
The killer could be a woman.
那是性别歧视  你这性别主义者
That's sexist. You're sexist.
让我来告诉你吧
Let me tell you something.
我说"他"的时候  我指的是男女统称
When I say he, I mean he or she.
我们两个之间
You know, between you and me,
还说什么政治正确的屁话
what is this PC bullshit anyway now?
还得用"他/她"代指"他"吗
You gotta say "he/she" for "he"
"他"本来指的就是"他/她"  懂我意思吗
when "he" already mean "he/she," you know what I mean?
我只觉得那样更尊重人
I just think it'll be more respectful
如果你觉得杀手也能是女人
if you think of the killer as a woman.
好吧
Okay.
告诉你我觉得什么叫尊重吧
Well, let me tell you what I think would be respectful...
那就是你给我从这只脚上取下一块皮肤样本
is if you got me a skin sample off this foot
别让我等得要吃伟哥了
before I start needing dick pills.
现在我去候诊室等着你
Now, I'ma be in the waiting room waiting.
没人知道伟大想法的来源
No one knows where great ideas come from,
但你总会记得灵光乍现的地点
but you always remember where you were when they came.
好了
There.
包皮环切术
优缺点
而这次  我的好主意来自于这一刻
And in this case, my great idea came the moment
当我走进诊室并且想到
I entered the exam room and realized
我要把这个婴儿的包皮切下来
I was going to cut the foreskin off this baby's dick
然后交给警长
and hand it to the sheriff.
-他生病几天了  -就两天
- How long has he been sick? - Just two days.
他没有发烧
He doesn't have a fever.
不幸中的万幸
That's a relief.
他的胸腔声音正常
His chest is clear.
他割过包皮了吗
Is he circumcised?
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
对  我这个问题太蠢了
Right, how dumb of me to ask.
我就在这呢  可以直接自己检查
I'm right here. I can just check myself.
来看看你下面是什么情况吧  小家伙
Let's see what you're packin' down there, champ.
哈里...  万德斯本格医生
Harry... Dr. Vanderspeigle,
你不用这么做的
you don't need to do that.
他没有割包皮  至少现在还没有
He's not circumcised. Not yet, anyway.
我们在考虑  但还没决定好
We were thinking about it but hadn't made a decision.
你不需要现在就做决定
And you don't need to make a decision right now.
越早越好
The sooner the better.
割掉包皮可以降低尿路感染的风险
Removing the foreskin reduces the risk of urinary tract infection.
-还有性病  -性病
- Also STDs. - STDs?
你想让你的孩子得淋病吗
Do you want your baby getting gonorrhea?
-你是认真在问我吗  -不  不是的
- Is that a real question? - No, it's not.
你应该考虑一下  那是个非常简单的手术
You should consider it. It's a very simple procedure.
我只需要通过手术切除
All I do is surgically remove the skin
包裹着你孩子老二顶端的皮肤
which covers the tip of your baby's prick.
给你
Here you go.
我要留着那只脚  保存好它
I'm keeping the foot so it can be stored properly.
死者脚上取下的DNA样本
我没意见
Fine by me.
它让我的办公室闻起来一股坏寿司味
Thing made my whole office smell like bad sushi.
我得把这个还给丽芙
I gotta get this back to Liv.
你懂的  女人都喜欢水桶
You know ladies love they buckets.
你可别说这是性别歧视  事实如此
Before you say that's sexist, that's just a fact.
-小麦  -妈妈  你来这儿干什么
- Hey, Maxie. - Mom, what are you doing?
我不能被人瞧见还在和自己妈妈玩
I can't be seen hanging out with my mother.
傻孩子
Don't be silly. Hey.
老师也是有午休时间的
Teachers get lunch breaks, too.
我只是顺路过来看看你
Just wanted to stop by and see how you're doing.
拜托快走吧
Please go!
我可以给你钱
I'll literally pay you.
这钱是我早上给你的
That's the money I gave you this morning.
那也是钱
Money is money.
好吧  但
Okay, just... Hey.
我只是想让你知道我爱你
I just wanted to tell you that I love you.
行吧
Okay.
-我能抱抱你吗  -不行
- Can I just get a hug? - No!
行吧  再见
Okay, great. Okay, bye.
爱你
Love you.
他就是那个贴外星人海报的小孩儿
Dude, that's the kid with the alien poster.
小麦
有人见过这个外星人吗
请联系小麦
演太空男孩儿呢
What, Space Boy?
就是他贴的外星人海报吗
He's the one with the alien posters?
你也是来笑话我的吗
You wanna make fun of me too?
不
No.
我相信你
Because I believe you.
压力  恐惧
Stress, fear.
难怪人类晚上会睡不着觉
No wonder humans can't sleep at night.
这水冷得能冻坏你的蛋
Imagine what that water would do to your balls?
至少我不会再想那小孩或是断脚的事儿了
At least I don't have to worry about the kid or the foot anymore.
发生什么事了  为什么你们会出现在我家湖边
What's going on here? Why are you on my beach?
警察办案  医生
It's official police business, Doc.
尸体其他部分一定在这儿的哪个地方
Rest of that body's got to be out there somewhere,
我打算找看看
and I plan on finding it.
你们太努力了  需要休息休息
You work too hard. You should take some time off.
请遵医嘱
Doctor's orders.
我有点担心
I am a little concerned about
这次行动的规模
the overall scale of this operation.
搜遍整个湖可不在我的预算范围内
You know, we don't have the budget to drag this whole lake.
那你的预算里包括
You got it in your budget
住在一个尸体遍布的小镇上吗
to live in a town littered with dead bodies?
帐可不是这样算的
Not really how budgets work.
整个搜查  真的太贵了
And this whole thing... It's just too expensive.
镇里绝对不会为零食付款的
I mean, the town is definitely not paying for snacks, okay?
那是克里特斯的狗粮
Those are Cletus's dog treats.
别吐
Hey, don't be spittin' that out!
那可是真的野牛肉  你到底啥毛病
That's real bison meat. What the hell's wrong with you?
-我去  这味道像怪味花生  -听着各位
- Dang it! God, it's like a gamey peanut. - Listen,
在场的各位都得打起精神
everyone here needs to get their head in the game.
必须将整个湖搜个遍
We're searching this entire lake.
找到尸体之前绝不停歇
We ain't gon' stop till we find that body.
是的  护士
Yes, nurse.
我屁股为了供你检查
I have very bad ass rash
起了一大片疹子  请吧
for you to examine, please.
来吧
Okay?
天  吓我一跳
Oh, my God, you scared me.
行了  走吧
Come on, let's go.
最近你总是闷闷不乐的
You've been so mopey lately.
你知道的  我朋友山姆死了
You do know my friend Sam died.
我知道
Yes, I know.
I know, I know,
很抱歉这真的太糟糕了
and I'm very sorry and it sucks,
但是为了让你不再去想这件事
but maybe to get your mind off of it,
跟我出去吧
you come out with me.
你这是又要带我去喂小松鼠吗
You taking me to feed baby squirrels again?
比这更好
This is even better.
他们要是能找到尸体  我就去自杀
They find that body, I'm gonna legit shit myself.
你说找点儿乐子的时候
When you said "Have some fun,"
我还以为是指吃顿美食或看场电影
I thought you meant dinner or maybe a movie.
得了吧  这可有场直播
Come on, we got a live show here.
万众期待得压轴大戏是出现一具被水泡胀的尸体
The finale, fingers crossed, is a bloated, dead corpse.
就这了吗  一场浮尸秀
So this is our night? A floater watch party?
就这个小镇来说已经很不错了
This town, I'll take what I can get.
而且  跟我约会的那个人  他鸽了我
Besides, I was dating this guy, and he sort of ghosted me.
完全断了联系
I mean, he stopped calling entirely
我甚至希望那个尸体就是他的
and I'm kind of hoping that's him out there, you know?
有个了结
Get some closure.
你猜我听说了什么  JT晚点有个趴
Also, you know what I heard? JT is having a party later.
JT
JT.
都快忘了这号人了
I haven't thought about him in forever.
简直不敢相信他还住在这里
I can't believe he's still around.
大家都住在这里
Well, I mean, everybody's still around.
没人会离开
Nobody gets out of here.
我们会的
We did.
一定会的
I'll give us that.
我俩都能实现自己的梦想
We both got out and chased our dreams.
-说得好  -是啊
- Damn right. - Yeah.
即使现实在身后追逐着我们
And reality chased us right back.
没错
Yeah.
竟然有点儿羡慕湖里的那具死尸
Yeah, starting to envy that body in the lake.
副警长  你怎么靠岸了
Deputy, why is your boat headed to shore?
镇长说他必须得回去
The mayor has to be brought back in.
他还有个会
He has an appointment.
船上是有人吐了吗
Is there somebody throwing up on that boat?
警长  我是镇长
Uh, hi, Sheriff. This is the mayor speaking.
我有个预先约定好的会
I just have a pre-existing appoi...
你晕船了吗
Are you seasick?
我们不会就因为
We don't halt justice
你肚子有点不舒服  就暂停司法
just 'cause your tummy's a little upset.
如果你想要小便  呕吐或是大便
If you gotta piss, puke, or shit,
你就去船侧边解决掉
you do it over the side of the boat.
与此同时  我们仍按计划行事
In the meantime, we stick to the plan.
你负责湖东边  我负责湖西边  完毕
You do the east lake grid; I do the west lake grid. Over.
收到  警长
Aye-aye, Sheriff.
要不  你喝点水
Perhaps if you drank some water?
我满嘴只有野牛味
All I taste is bison.
我不喜欢这种感觉
I don't like this feeling.
甚至这条狗都让我感到紧张
Even this dog is making me nervous.
我还记得我不知道恐惧是什么感觉的时候
I remember when I didn't know the meaning of fear.
我的飞船坠毁后  我独自生活了两周
After my ship crashed, I was on my own for two weeks.
四个月前
新墨西哥州
外星人在一个外星球上  处处危机四伏
An alien on an alien planet, danger everywhere.
没有什么能让我担心
None of it concerned me.
没有恐惧感能让我做出大胆的时尚选择
Not knowing fear allowed me to make bold fashion choices.
我不认为他们会找到尸体
I don't think they're gonna find a body.
别这样  积极点
Come on, stay positive.
那里应该是哈里的小屋
I think that's Harry's cabin over there.
真奢华啊
Fancy.
我好奇当我们分手的时候  一半的小屋能值多少钱
I wonder what half of it will be worth when we split up.
我记起来哈里会让我想到谁了
I remember who Harry reminds me of.
-谁  -丹尼·奥利弗
- Who? - Danny Oliver.
-老天  是带你去毕业舞会的那个  -是的  是他
- My God, he took you to prom. - Yes, he did, right?
-是他带我去的  -天呐
- Yes, he did. - Oh, God.
你还记得他跳的那支《爷钱够你花》
You remember him dancing to "Got Your Money"?
*小淫猫*
*Hey, Dirty!*
*宝贝  爷钱有的是  你别担心*
*Baby, I got your money, don't you worry*
*你最好把钱都给我*
*You better give me that money, ooh!*
-我的天  -就现在
- Oh, my damn. - Right now!
*宝贝  给你的份爷有的是*
*Baby, I got your money*
-没错  -*别但心*
- Yes! - *Don't you worry*
*我说*
*Said hey*
*宝贝  爷的钱够你花*
*Baby, I got your money*
*我说*
*Hey, said hey*
*宝贝  爷钱有的是  别担心*
*Baby, I got your money, don't you worry*
警长  或许  我应该上岸  搜寻下海岸线
Sheriff, maybe I should go in and check the shoreline?
根据现状
Based on the current,
尸体很有可能已经被水冲上岸了
it is highly probable the body has already washed up.
我知道是怎么回事  镇长还是不舒服
I know what's going on. The mayor's still sick.
你继续执行任务  副警长  我们还有具尸体要找
You stay on mission, Deputy. We got a body to find.
这个人不会停手的
This guy's not going to give up.
我不能慌张  我只是需要一个计划
I can't panic. I just need a plan.
如果他们找到了尸体
If they find the body,
我就说那是我的双胞胎兄弟  弗雷德里克
I'll say it's my twin brother, Frederico.
花花公子  酗酒  不怎么会游泳
Playboy, drinker, bad swimmer.
下来  小家伙
Whoa. Down, boy.
快下来  小家伙
Down, boy.
下来  这是我的尸体
Down! This is my body.
这是我的尸体
This is my body.
不  快放开
No, let go!
哈里  你在家吗
Harry? Are you home?
是的  我在家  我就是站在这  啥也没做
Yes, I'm home just standing here doing nothing.
不错  看上去像是个有趣的夜晚
Oh, cool. Looks like a fun night.
你们在这干什么
What are you doing here?
我们本来在沙滩上看着他们在湖里打捞
We were down at the beach watching the lake being dragged.
就像我们小镇版的汽车电影院那样
It's like our town's version of a drive-in.
我们可以借用一下你的厕所吗
Can we use your bathroom?
麻烦了
Please?
厕所在后面
It's back there.
但是之后你们得立马离开
But then you have to leave right away.
-我非常忙  -是的  我们知道  忙着闲
- I'm very busy. - Yeah, we know, doing nothing.
我不喜欢他了  是非常不喜欢他了
I'm over him. Like, so over him.
我甚至因我喜欢过他而感到尴尬
Like, I'm embarrassed that I was into him.
你为什么要翻他的东西
Why are you going through his stuff?
你能以此更多的了解一个人
You can find out a lot about a guy this way.
他所有的维生素都有
He's got all the vitamins.
维生素A B C  天呐
A, B, C--oh, my God.
都是按照字母表顺序储藏的
They're stored in alphabetical order.
他是个疯子
He's a maniac.
我太"性奋"了
I'm so turned on.
我们准备走了
We are gonna go.
你千万别进去
Do not go in there.
我是开玩笑的  我没有在你浴室里大便
I'm just kidding. I didn't shit in your bathroom.
我得去参加派对了  不好意思  你没被邀请去
Gotta go to a party. Sorry, you're not invited.
差不多算是个女生之夜
Kinda a girl's night thing, so yeah.
-好的  -认真的  没什么大不了的
- Okay. - Seriously, it's not a big deal.
就是  我的前任  JT  他非常成功
It's just, like, my ex, JT, he's, like, really successful
他在山上有个超级大的房子
and he's got this, like, really big house in the hills
他求着我过去
and he's, like, begging me to go,
这...对他来说很尴尬
which...embarrassing for him, you know?
那我很疑惑你为什么还在这
Then I'm confused why you're still here.
-快去吧  -好了  没事了
- Go. - No, we're good.
我懂了  那我们下次再见
I get it. So we'll see you another time.
谢谢
Thank you.
就像是他吃醋了但几乎没藏住
It's like he's jealous but barely hiding it.
他藏得挺好的
He's hiding it pretty well.
他可能会跟踪我们
He's probably gonna follow us.
不  他不会的
No, he's not.
-我的天呐  -你太古怪了
- Oh, my God. - You're so weird.
姑娘们  你们带身份证了吗
Hey, you girls got ID?
你们在这干什么
Oh, what are you doing here?
那个贱人打电话搬救兵了
This bitch called in for reinforcements.
达茜
Aww, D'arce.
谢谢  该死的  我们开始吧
Thank you. Let's do the damn thing.
这给你
Give it to you.
你有更给力的东西吗
Ugh, do you have anything stronger?
我吸了足够塞奇喝一周的奶
Pumped Sage enough milk for a week.
-我要出来浪一浪  -你看起来真性感
- I'm trying to be out‐out. - Ooh, you look hot.
你为什么打扮得像个黑帮老大的妻子
Ooh, why are you dressed like a mob wife?
你为什么不这么穿
Why aren't you?
我有丈夫  你只有猫
I have a husband. You have a cat.
而且
Besides,
这是塞奇出生以来我第一次晚上出来浪
this is the first night I've been out since Sage was born.
我才不要穿野马队卫衣和牛仔裤
I'm not gonna waste it on a Broncos jersey and jeans.
我看中一个人了  我想跟他
I see somebody I wanna talk to...
用臀部交流感情
with my butt.
好吧
'Kay.
小心点
Hey, watch it.
-滚远点  熟女  -熟女
- Kick rocks, cougar. - Cougar?
我们认识一个住在这里的家伙
We know the guy that lives here,
也许  我们会让他把你撵出这里
so maybe we could have him just kick your ass right out of here.
谁  JT的老爸  他不在镇上  夫人
Who, JT's dad? He's outta town, lady.
夫人
Lady?
看看这两个老太婆
Check out the MILFs.
你是邀请我来参加高中派对吗
Did you invite me to a high school party?
天啊  我靠
Oh, God. Holy shit.
不不  这不好玩  行吗
No, no, no, this isn't funny, okay?
我浪费时间开了48公里车  雇了保姆
I wasted a 30‐mile drive, a babysitter,
还抹上了最好的口红来到这
and I smeared my best lipstick to be here.
-抱歉  -天啊
- I'm sorry. - Oh, my God.
达茜在哪  我靠
Where's D'Arcy? Oh, shit.
-我要杀了她  -天啊  天啊
- I'm gonna kill her. - Oh, God, oh, God. Oh, God.
你跳得真好
You're a good dancer.
你很苗条
And you're skinny.
像蟋蟀一样
Like a cricket.
-你想要上楼吗  -为什么  楼上有什么
- You wanna take it upstairs? - Why, what's upstairs?
不不
Oh, no, no, no.
天啊  牙套
Oh, my God, braces? Ugh.
高中派对
Ugh, high school party.
你的新男朋友怎么样  你跟他做过引体向上吗
How's your new boyfriend. You get into his Pull‐Ups yet?
我觉得刚才那是他第一次勃起
I think that was his first boner.
我猜你忘了JT的儿子也叫JT
I guess that you forgot that JT also has a son named JT?
他自恋又不是我的错
It's not my fault that he is a narcissist.
好吧  好吧
Wow, okay, okay.
不好意思
Excuse me.
-干什么  -你们要来点吗
- Why? - You guys want some?
太好了  我们在Z时代毒品老巢
Oh, great. We're in a Gen Z drug den.
那是山姆的  你是从哪搞来的
Hey, these are Sam's. Where'd you get these?
我的口袋里
From my pocket.
晕  她的意思是  是谁把这些给你的
Burnout, she means who gave them to you?
这个处方是他死后开的
This prescription was written after he died.
医生没有给你开这些药
You weren't prescribed these.
我要把这个拿走  如果你对此有意见
I'm taking them, and if you have a problem with that,
我要报警了
I'm gonna call the cops.
-这是怎么回事  -我们走吧
- What was that about? - Let's just get out of here.
等等  杰伊
Wait. Jay?
靠
Oh, shit.
这些孩子们怎么比我们还颓
How are all these children more wasted than us?
够了  我要回家去抱我的宝宝了
Okay, yeah, I'm going home to snuggle my baby.
你们两个  你们需要回家了
You two, you need families.
又或者是需要律师
Or maybe a lawyer.
真是太难为情了  帮我
This is embarrassing. Help me.
好的好的  来吧
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Let's do it.
好了
All right.
今晚的事很抱歉
Sorry about tonight.
你还太年轻了  不知道那个派对到底有多糟糕
You're too young to know how sorry that party really was.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - Course.
去睡觉吧
Just get to bed.
等一下
Oh, hang on, um...
我知道你最近过得很艰难
I know you've been going through a hard time lately.
不管你什么时候遇到了困难
Whenever you're having a rough time,
就烧一些雪松  给自己熏香吧
just burn some of this cedar and pull the smoke around you.
这是我爸教我的  会有帮助的
Something my dad taught me. It'll help.
真奇怪  不过好吧
That's weird, but okay.
谢谢  特瑞弗翠丝女士
Thanks, Ms. Twelvetrees.
阿斯塔  你准备好了吗
Asta, are you ready?
阿斯塔
Asta?
山姆
Sam!
你没事吧
You okay?
-我们走吧  -好  我们走
- Let's get out of here. - Yeah, let's do it.
坐前面  公主  我可不是专车司机
Up front, princess. I'm not a chauffeur.
我的意思是  好吧
I mean‐oh, okay.
我们就这么做
That's how we're doing it?
对  我们就这么做
Yep, that's how we're doing it.
没问题
No problem.
今晚就这样吧  医生
We're calling it a night, Doc,
但是我们明天继续
but we'll be back tomorrow.
有具尸体还不见着呢
There's a dead body out there somewhere
我们找不到就誓不罢休
and we're not gonna rest until we find it.
不过我们现在要回家休息了
Except we are going to go home and rest now.
克里特斯
Hey, Cletus!
回来
Hey! Get back here, boy!
你闻到什么了
Hey! What you smell?
克里特斯
Cletus!
你发现什么了
What you got, boy? -
见鬼  它有发现了
Oh, hell. He onto something!
-他不能进去  -去吧
- He cannot go in there. - Go on, boy!
难怪他疯了似的
No wonder he's losing his mind.
是野牛肉
It's bison.
你有肉
You got meat.
我喜欢吃肉
I like meat.
我也喜欢
I like meat, too, you know?
我尝过兔肉
I've tried rabbit.
我还吃过一次麋鹿
And I tried moose once.
我叔叔做的  我吃了  但是不喜欢
My uncle made them. I ate it, but I didn't like it.
好吧  这里没什么好看的
Okay, well, there's nothing to see here.
至少我想吃肉时知道去哪儿找了  对吗
At least I know where I can come if I need meat, right?
来吧  克里特斯
Come on, here, Cletus!
叫我丽芙
And Liv.
嗨  爸爸
Hey, Dad.
你怎么就醒了
Why are you awake?
-别告诉我你一晚上都在等我  -没有
- Please don't tell me you waited up for me. - No.
-吃早餐吗  -好啊
- Breakfast? - Oh, my God, please.
炒鸡蛋  你最喜欢的
Scrambled eggs, your favorite.
看起来不错
This looks good.
是个女孩
It was a girl.
是个女婴
The baby was a girl.
我以为没有我她会过得更好
I thought she'd be better off without me,
但如果这不是真的呢
but what if that's not true?
如果  如果她应该和我在一起呢
What if--what if she's supposed to be with me?
你是那孩子的母亲
You're a mother to that child.
你们之间的纽带永远不会断
That bond can never be broken.
这是母亲给孩子的礼物
It's a mother's gift.
不管孩子在哪儿
Wherever that child is,
你都能感受到她
you'll always be able to sense her.
有一天
One day,
这种联系会让你们团聚
that connection will bring you back together.
乔餐厅
-给你  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Oh, thank you.
我俩的袋子一样
We both have the same bag.
是啊
Oh, um, yeah.
我给你的办公桌抽屉买了把锁
I was just buying a lock for your desk drawer.
山姆过去把病例单放在那儿
It's where Sam used to keep all his prescription pads.
你呢
What about you?
我也有些东西要锁起来
I also have some things to lock away.
仓库锁
你到底是谁  哈里·万德斯本格
Who even are you, Harry Vanderspeigle?
就是一个...
Just a...
人
guy.
人人都有秘密
Everybody has secrets.
恐惧是很好的动力
Fear is such a great motivator.
让人把秘密锁起来
It makes people lock those secrets away.
但每有一个人把秘密锁起来
But for every one person locking away their secrets,
就有两个人想发现真相
there are two more people seeking to uncover the truth.
吓人吧
Scary, right?
好恶心
He's disgusting.
肯定是他把你的自行车刹车弄坏的
He definitely cut the brakes on your bike.
我要走近看看
I need to get a closer look.
别  别去
No, don't. Don't do it.
什么鬼
What the hell?
不友好的獾  烧烤酒吧
新墨西哥某地
于是我盯着那个外星人的黄眼睛
So I look that alien son of a bitch right in his jaundiced eyes
直截了当地说道
and I said in no uncertain terms,
"别惹我"
"I'm not the one to mess with."
我说  "小子  我不知道你是从哪儿来的
I said, "Boy, I don't know where you're from
我他妈也不在乎
"And I don't much give a flying duck's fart.
有一件事是肯定的
"One thing's for certain, two things for sure.
你最好离我远点"
You best stay the hell away from me."
他向我走来
Well, he come at me.
我一脚踢在他的屁股上  把他踢飞了
I kicked his alien ass all the way to the next county.
该死的东西顺走了我的马儿和帽子
Damn thing got away with my horse and my hat,
但我知道他不敢再惹我了
but I knew he wouldn't mess with me again.
难以置信  这就是为什么我们要四处旅行
Unbelievable. See, this is why we like traveling around
和其他遭遇外星人的人见面
meeting other alien experiencers.
像这样的故事
Stories like that.
我们在网上看到你的视频
When we saw your videos online,
就知道一定要跟你谈谈
we knew we had to come speak with you.
你说你在哪儿见到外星人来着
Where did you say you actually saw the alien again?
你知道他去哪儿了吗
Do you know where he was headed?
小娘子
Well, little lady,
一喝酒就打开了话匣子
I've been letting this liquor speak for me
我想我已经说得够多了
and I think I said too much already.
不过你可以在我的书里看到
But you can read about that in the book I'm writing.
酷  你在写书
Oh, cool. You're writing a book.
小娘子
Well, well, little lady.
你干什么
What are you doing--
天啊  你疯了吗
Oh, my God! Are you insane?
你杀了他
You killed him?
我们不应该杀人的
We're not supposed to kill people!
我们的任务不是这样的
Those aren't our orders!
看来我们接的是不同的任务
Looks like you and I have different orders.